<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sobit Akhmedov</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sobit Akhmedov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon software engineer interview</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2016/07/08/amazon-software-engineer-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2016/07/08/amazon-software-engineer-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/amazon-we-pioneer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Amazon - We Pioneer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently contacted by a technical recruiter from Amazon. The company was hosting an interview event for software
engineers to join a team in their Berlin office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole process from being contacted to signing the contract took two months. I would like to share my experience on
how it went in general as well as what I believe helped me pass it successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I failed to mention something important in this article, feel free to start a discussion in the comments section.
There I will try to be as detailed as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go from PHP engineer&#39;s perspective</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2016/02/25/go-from-php-engineers-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2016/02/25/go-from-php-engineers-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.org/gopher.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gopher&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a PHP engineer, have you ever asked yourself whether you need to master other programming languages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/&#34;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt; has been the language of choice for building a full-stack monolithic applications for many companies and many
years. Furthermore, in the last 5 years frameworks (&lt;a href=&#34;http://symfony.com/&#34;&gt;Symfony&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://laravel.com/&#34;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://framework.zend.com/&#34;&gt;Zend&lt;/a&gt;), tools (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getcomposer.org/&#34;&gt;Composer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Seldaek/monolog&#34;&gt;Monolog&lt;/a&gt;) and
rapidly growing community (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php-fig.org/&#34;&gt;PHP-FIG&lt;/a&gt;) helped many engineers to build enterprise level software applications. Many
companies, such as Facebook, Yahoo!, Wikipedia, Wordpress, Tumblr, had pure PHP in their early days, and that didn&amp;rsquo;t
hold them back from becoming successful over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a successful business grows, so grows the number of engineers it needs to support the growth. Organizational
structure of the company indicates that the existing monolith is better be split apart. At some point the strategy
stabilizes and teams now focus on independent services instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we will try to evaluate how far can PHP alone take us and where &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; can step in and solve problems we
will face down the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking Hackerrank - Encryption</title>
      <link>http://example.org/2016/02/18/cracking-hackerrank-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/2016/02/18/cracking-hackerrank-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a friend of mine loves to say, &amp;ldquo;The best way to learn a programming language is to start writing algorithms in it&amp;rdquo;.
While that most probably won&amp;rsquo;t make you the language expert, there&amp;rsquo;s a high chance that you will face most of the data
structures it provides as well as feel the power of it&amp;rsquo;s unique language constructs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;re lots of good resources to help you get started, but I prefer to spend my spare time on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackerrank.com/&#34;&gt;Hackerrank&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s free, has pleasant user interface and a solid selection of algorithmic
problems conveniently broken down into categories and difficulty levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After solving each problem, the whole analyzing part is usually getting thrown out. And that pointed me to the idea of
writing the way of thinking into blog posts. Always good to look back and see how good you were and how bad was your
English. So let&amp;rsquo;s get it started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our today&amp;rsquo;s problem - &amp;ldquo;Encryption&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackerrank.com/challenges/encryption&#34;&gt;link to the challenge&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>